Get off our land.
40 Acres is a action, thriller, drama film directed by R.T. Thorne.
Hailey Freeman and her family are the last descendants of African American
farmers who settled in rural Canada after the Civil War.
In a famine-decimated near future, they now struggle to safeguard their farm, as they make
one last stand against a vicious militia hell-bent on taking their 40 Acres.
Hailey Freeman, played by Danielle Deadwyler.
Emanuel Freeman, played by Kataem O'Connor.
Galen, played by Michael Greyeyes.
Dawn, played by Milcania Diaz-Rojas.
Raine, played by Leenah Robinson.
Danis Freeman, played by Jaeda LeBlanc.
40 Acres is a 2024 Canadian post-apocalyptic
thriller film written and directed by R.
The film stars Danielle Deadwyler as a matriarch of descendants of African-American
farmers who settled in 1875 in rural Canada after the first Civil War.
Two hundred years later, they are trying to survive in a decimated future.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 6, 2024, and
was theatrically released in Canada on July 4, 2025 by Mongrel Media.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, receiving nomintations at the Black Reel Awards, NAACP Image
Awards and winning three Directors Guild of Canada Awards, including the Impact Award for Thorne.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.